[
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 128,
        "id": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lord Robert",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stately baron",
            "job": "I rule this province.",
            "heal": "Very well.",
            "keyword1": "PROV",
            "keyword2": "WORD",
            "answer1": "My Lady Marcy can tell thee more!",
            "answer2": "I know but one of three syllables.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou wish to know it now?",
            "yesanswer": "It is 'amo' seek ye now the other parts!",
            "noanswer": "Perhaps another time."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 31,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lady Marcy",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A charming lady",
            "job": "I rule with my Lord.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "RULE",
            "keyword2": "PROV",
            "answer1": "This province.",
            "answer2": "Our people believe in love as a way of life and live it to the fullest!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek love?",
            "yesanswer": "Then may thou find it!",
            "noanswer": "Then thou shalt not find it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 31,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 2,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 64,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Suzanna",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A lovely lady",
            "job": "I am a lady in waiting.",
            "heal": "Overworked!",
            "keyword1": "LADY",
            "keyword2": "HORN",
            "answer1": "I serve Marcy.",
            "answer2": "There is a paladin by the name of Malchor. He can lead thee to the silver horn!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou allowed to be in here?",
            "yesanswer": "I doubt it! Thou should leave!",
            "noanswer": "Thou should leave!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 3,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Life.",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "An ankh",
            "job": "I resonate thoughts.",
            "heal": "I exist.",
            "keyword1": "RESO",
            "keyword2": "LOVE",
            "answer1": "What are thy thoughts?",
            "answer2": "Seek ye the candle of love for only with it and two other parts might thou enter the abyss!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have it?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Ask the bard beyond the secret passage!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 61,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 4,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "the pass guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "I guard the passages.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "PASS",
            "keyword2": "DANG",
            "answer1": "There is no danger.",
            "answer2": "Well not compared to a dungeon altar room!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou solved the altars?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "From them a three part key is gained, needed to enter the chamber of the codex!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 5,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a gate guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A guard",
            "job": "A gate guard",
            "heal": "Top notch.",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "ABBE",
            "answer1": "To the abbey.",
            "answer2": "Here, in the oak grove many find the meaning of peace and love!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou saturated with love?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou need not be here!",
            "noanswer": "Visit the small shrine within the abbey!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 6,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Derek the Bard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A young bard playing a lute.",
            "job": "I am a bard, I sing songs.",
            "heal": "Pretty good.",
            "keyword1": "SONG",
            "keyword2": "CAND",
            "answer1": "Oh, all types.",
            "answer2": "The candle of love is found in a secret place hidden off Lock Lake!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou like this one?",
            "yesanswer": "Thanks, I just wrote it!",
            "noanswer": "Alas, it was new."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 84,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 7,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Chinup",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small but stately child.",
            "job": "I welcome thee unto the Abbey!",
            "heal": "Very well, thank you!",
            "keyword1": "GROV",
            "keyword2": "OAK ",
            "answer1": "A grove of oak.",
            "answer2": "There four profession types seek truth!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou here in search of love?",
            "yesanswer": "Perhaps then the oak grove!",
            "noanswer": "Perhaps then the oak grove."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 8,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Diane",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A tall woman.",
            "job": "I counsel those who enter the grove.",
            "heal": "Good.",
            "keyword1": "COUN",
            "keyword2": "LOVE",
            "answer1": "Herein thou may find insights into love, within thyself or the others here in the grove.",
            "answer2": "Ask the others.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most loving person?",
            "yesanswer": "Doubtful!",
            "noanswer": "Strive for love!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 9,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Benjamin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A solemn bard.",
            "job": "I relate love and compassion.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "LOVE",
            "keyword2": "COMP",
            "answer1": "When the three combine in eight ways love alone is compassion.",
            "answer2": "Of the eight avatar attributes compassion is derived from love alone.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou well?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good.",
            "noanswer": "Too bad..."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 35,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 10,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Deirdre",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A druid, lost in thought.",
            "job": "I ponder love and justice.",
            "heal": "Fine.",
            "keyword1": "LOVE",
            "keyword2": "JUST",
            "answer1": "When three build eight, truth tempered by love becomes justice!",
            "answer2": "Justice is one of the eight avatar virtues and derives from truth and love.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou?",
            "yesanswer": "Most good.",
            "noanswer": "I see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 11,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Thomas",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A hearty tinker.",
            "job": "I am thinking of love's part in sacrifice.",
            "heal": "Fine",
            "keyword1": "LOVE",
            "keyword2": "SACR",
            "answer1": "Love of others and the courage to face even death is self-sacrifice.",
            "answer2": "Sacrifice is built upon the motive of love and the ability of courage.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Thyself?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Shame."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 41,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 12,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lastro",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A solemn ranger.",
            "job": "I follow the spiritual path.",
            "heal": "Most well.",
            "keyword1": "SPIR",
            "keyword2": "BEIN",
            "answer1": "My spirituality is not a religion, but a searching to know and improve my own inner being.",
            "answer2": "My being is based on my own truth, love and courage.",
            "yesnoquestion": "And thee?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "So sad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 44,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 13,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Humlock",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mumbling beggar.",
            "job": "I seek salvation",
            "heal": "Not so good.",
            "keyword1": "MUMB",
            "keyword2": "SALV",
            "answer1": "The...ankh... spoke to me!",
            "answer2": "I am but a poor destitute beggar I have nothing!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Will you give me some money?",
            "yesanswer": "I would be soooo grateful....",
            "noanswer": "But I am in most dire need!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 88,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 14,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Malchor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A bold paladin.",
            "job": "I solve quests",
            "heal": "Just now fully healed!",
            "keyword1": "QUES",
            "keyword2": "HORN",
            "answer1": "My last quest took me near Spiritwood.",
            "answer2": "Some say that the silver horn is buried on a small isle off the tip of Spiritwood.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou on a quest?",
            "yesanswer": "Best of luck to thee!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 43,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 15,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Brother Antos",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise druid.",
            "job": "I hold great wisdom.",
            "heal": "I am getting old and frail.",
            "keyword1": "WISD",
            "keyword2": "CAND",
            "answer1": "What dost thou ask of me?",
            "answer2": "Thou dost need the candle of love to enter the abyss.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know where to find it?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good.",
            "noanswer": "Meditate on love at our shrine."
        }
    }
]